<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Bhim Chaulagain</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Bhim Chaulagain</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>B. Chaulagain {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ecology and Evolution of Infectious Diseases (EEID)</title>
      <link>/project/eeid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/eeid/</guid>
      <description>


  




&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/day84_log.png&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/day84_log.png&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epidemic invasion by newly introduced insects’ pests and pathogens pose serious threat to biodiversity, ecosystem function and human health worldwide, with socio-economic burden extensively larger than from natural disasters. Pathogens demonstrating long distance dispersal (LDD) are of more concern because of their ability to spread fast and remain cryptic (ability to stay asymptomatic for a certain period of time) as distant foci may have developed through surprisingly small concentrations of inoculum dispersed at larger spatial scales. I am conducting series of field studies to unlock the spatio-temporal spread and the efficacy of mitigation practices (e.g. timing and extent of fungicide applications and other broad-scale population protection) on epidemics caused by pathogens exhibiting long distance dispersal using wheat stripe rust as an experimental model. Results are validated using spatailly explicit SIR models with model parameteres relevant to wheat stripe rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publication (Coming soon 😄, Please check back later)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction Modelling and Management of Sugarcane Rust</title>
      <link>/project/sr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/sr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  




&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/SR.jpg&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/SR.jpg&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

Breeding for sugarcane rust resistance is challenging as sugarcane has a complex genome and sugarcane breeding is a long process. This limits the frequent release of resistant cultivars for commercial production. Management of sugarcane rusts in Florida primarily relies on the use of fungicides and application schedules are typically based on information from disease scouting. Better knowledge of rust epidemiology is required to assist in optimizing the timing of fungicide application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the objective of this study was to characterize the progress of both brown rust and orange rust of sugarcane in the field across multiple years and develop the predictive models based on weather variables to help growers in timing the fungicide application. I also evaluated biological activity and physical modes of action of several fungicides in vitro and in situ for their efficacy to control sugarcane brown and orange rust diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;•	&lt;strong&gt;Chaulagain, B.&lt;/strong&gt;, Small, I., Shine, J., Clyde, F., Raid, R. N., and Rott, P. 2020. Weather based predictive modeling of sugarcane orange rust in Florida. Phytopathology, 110:626-632. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1094/PHYTO-06-19-0211-R&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1094/PHYTO-06-19-0211-R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;•	Sanjel, S., &lt;strong&gt;Chaulagain, B.&lt;/strong&gt;, Small, I. M., Comstock, J. C., Hincapie, M., Raid, R. N., and Rott, P. 2019. Comparison of progress of brown rust and orange rust and conditions conducive for severe epidemic development during the sugarcane crop season in Florida. Plant Disease, 103:825-831. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1094/PDIS-05-18-0862-RE&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1094/PDIS-05-18-0862-RE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;•	&lt;strong&gt;Chaulagain, B.&lt;/strong&gt;, Dufault, N., Raid, R. N., and Rott, P. 2019. Sensitivity of sugarcane rust fungi to fungicides in uredospore germination and detached leaf bioassays. Crop Protection, 117:86-93. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cropro.2018.11.014&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cropro.2018.11.014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;•	&lt;strong&gt;Chaulagain, B.&lt;/strong&gt;, Raid, R. N., Dufault, N., Santen, E. V., and Rott, P. 2019. Application timing of fungicides for the management of sugarcane orange rust. Crop Protection, 119:141-146. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cropro.2019.01.007&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cropro.2019.01.007&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;•	&lt;strong&gt;Chaulagain, B.&lt;/strong&gt;, Raid, R. N., and Rott, P. 2019. Timing and frequency of fungicide applications for the management of sugarcane brown rust. Crop Protection, 124:104826. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cropro.2019.05.020&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cropro.2019.05.020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epidemiology and Management of Wheat Stripe Rust</title>
      <link>/project/wsr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/wsr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  




&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/WSR.jpg&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/WSR.jpg&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

Wheat culitvar mixtures (resistant and suceptible) can be used as a low cost method for suppressing many foliar diseases including wheat stripe rust. Series of field experiments conducted in Nepal suggested that there is positive correlation between the disease suppression and increased proportion of resistant cultivar in the mixture (My MS research project 😄). Mechanism of disease suppression involves dilution effect, barrier effect, induced resistance and microclimate modification. Additionally, this approach can be integrated with chemical (strobilurin and triazoles) applications for better managment of the wheat stripe rust epidemics. More information on this can be found in one of our publication and several other literatures as well. Please follow this publication if you are interested in our research regarding the effect of wheat cultivar mixtures on wheat stripe ruust severity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publication:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaulagain, B.&lt;/strong&gt;, Khatri Chhetri, G. B., Shrestha, S. M., Sharma, S., Sharma-Poudyal, D., and Lamichhane, J. R. 2017. Effect of two-component cultivar mixtures on development of wheat yellow rust disease in the field and greenhouse in the Nepal Himalayas. Journal of General Plant Pathology, 83:131-139. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10327-017-0705-z&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10327-017-0705-z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
